AMAAN SINGH

336 Heron Way | Vacaville, CA 95688 | (510) 660-1764 | amsingh@ucsd.edu

OBJECTIVE

I believe my sphere of interest lies in the engineering world as a whole. I am passionate about the opportunity to use my professional and social skills to help drive a business forward, and am eager for more real-world experience in this area.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego

La Jolla, CA

Bachelor of Science, Major in Computer Engineering

Graduation Date: Jun 2024

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

SPIS Summer Program Project

La Jolla, CA

Python Script Developer

Jun 2021 - Jun 2021

- A script that involves my knowledge of Python, web scraping, APIs, and HTTP requests
- A script that takes your Soundcloud playlist and converts it into a Spotify playlist

Software Engineering Class

La Jolla, CA

Web Developer

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

- Meant to simulate how we would work in teams
- Worked on an innovative web project where we learned modern day web development practices
- We as a team had created a scalable, local first booklist website

Intro Comp Vision

La Jolla, CA

Computer Vision Developer

Jan 2023 - Mar 2023

- The goal of computer vision is to compute properties of the three-dimensional world from images and video
- Introduced to computer vision, including such topics as 3D shape reconstruction through stereo, motion estimation, and image classification
- · Used Python and Opency

Autonomous Vehicle Development

La Jolla, CA

Autonomous Vehicle Developer

Mar 2023 - Jun 2023

- Helped develop an autonomous vehicle using ROS, Python, and hardware components
- Skills learned include project management, adhering to a budget and business planning, working within time constraints, designing to specifications, demonstrating performance, and delivering a well-documented project that others can build on
- Introduced and did development in the following areas: Computer Vision Algorithms for Navigation, On-vehicle vs.
 off-vehicle computation, Computer learning systems such as Neural Networks, Locomotion Systems, Vehicle
 Steering and Traction Control, Dead Reckoning, Odometry, Sensor Fusion, Global Positioning Based (GPS) AutoPilot limitations, Simulation, Power Management

WORK EXPERIENCE

A-One Towing Bookkeeping

Richmond, CA

Computer Programmer

- Efficiently produced consistent and diligent work
- Development of technological skills
- Involved in leading team meetings

Assist Program Tutor Crockett, CA

Program Tutor

- Assisted students in struggling subject fields
- Engaged in a leadership role
- Built communicative skills

SKILLS

Languages: Python, C, C++, Java, HTML5/CSS, JavaScript, R, Verilog Frameworks: Django, Flask, React, OpenCV, ROS2, and other multiple front-end frameworks Tools: Unix, Git, Selenium, APIs, Requests, API development in Node.js, Docker, Excel, Powerpoint, Google Suite, Python package development